<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!--
Copyright (C) 2007-2015  Brian Langenberger
This work is licensed under the
Creative Commons Attribution-Share Alike 3.0 United States License.
To view a copy of this license, visit
http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/us/ or send a letter to
Creative Commons,
171 Second Street, Suite 300,
San Francisco, California, 94105, USA.
-->
<manpage>
  <utility>tracklint</utility>
  <author>Brian Langenberger</author>
  <section>1</section>
  <name>checks and fixes minor track metadata errors automatically</name>
  <title>Track Checker</title>
  <synopsis>[OPTIONS] &lt;track 1&gt; [track 2] ....</synopsis>
  <description>
    tracklint takes a list of audio tracks,
    examines their metadata for common problems and suggests fixes for them.
    If directories are given, tracklint searches them recursively
    and suggests fixes for any audio tracks found.
    tracklint can also perform any suggested metadata fixes if
    requested, and undo any performed fixes if an undo database was
    used.
  </description>
  <options>
    <option short="h" long="help">show a list of options and exit</option>
    <option long="fix">
      perform tracklint's suggested fixes on the given audio tracks
    </option>
    <option short="V" long="verbose" arg="verbosity">
      The level of output to display.
      Choose between 'normal', 'quiet' and 'debug'.
    </option>
  </options>
  <element name="fixes">
    <p>The following fixes are performed on each track:</p>
    <ul>
      <li>
        Leading zeroes are stripped from track number and album number fields.
        For example, a track number value of "01"
        is changed to "1".
      </li>
      <li>
        If the track number field is between 100 and 999, the leading digit
        becomes the album number and trailing two digits becomes
        the track number.
        For example, a track number value of "213"
        results in an album number of "2" and a track number of
        "13".
      </li>
      <li>
        If the performer name is the same as the artist name,
        the redundant performer name field is removed.
      </li>
      <li>
        Leading or trailing whitespace is removed from fields.
        For example, a track name value of "Some Title " becomes
        "Some Title".
      </li>
      <li>
        Empty fields are removed.
      </li>
      <li>
        Embedded images with invalid metadata fields such as width or height
        are fixed.
      </li>
      <li>
        ID3v2 and ID3v1 tags are stripped from FLAC files.
      </li>
      <li>
        FLAC files with misordered STREAMINFO blocks are reordered.
      </li>
      <li>
        A WAVEFORMATEXTENSIBLE_CHANNEL_MASK tag is added to
        multi-channel or 24 bits-per-sample FLAC files
        if one isn't present in its metadata.
      </li>
    </ul>
  </element>
</manpage>
