<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<manpage>
  <utility>track2track</utility>
  <author>Brian Langenberger</author>
  <section>1</section>
  <name>convert audio tracks</name>
  <title>Audio File Converter</title>
  <synopsis>[OPTIONS] &lt;track 1&gt; [track 2] ...</synopsis>
  <description>
    track2track converts audio tracks from one format to another.
  </description>
  <options>
    <option short="h" long="help">show a list of options and exit</option>
    <option short="V" long="verbose" arg="verbosity">
      The level of output to display.
      Choose between 'normal', 'quiet' and 'debug.
    </option>
  </options>
  <options category="conversion">
    <option short="t" long="type" arg="type">
      The audio format to convert the given tracks to.
      For a list of available audio formats, try: -t help.
    </option>
    <option short="q" long="quality" arg="quality">
      The desired quality of the converted tracks.
      For a list of available quality modes for a given format, try: -q help
    </option>
    <option short="d" long="dir" arg="directory">
      The target directory for the converted tracks.
      If none is given, the current working directory is used.
      If the target directory does not exist,
      it will be created automatically.
      This option is not compatible with -o
    </option>
    <option long="format" arg="string">
      The format string to use for new filenames.
      Template fields are replaced with metadata values when
      new tracks are created.  All other text is left as-is.
      If this option is omitted, a default format string is used.
    </option>
    <option short="o" long="output" arg="filename">
      An explicit output filename for the converted track.
      With this option, only a single input track is allowed.
      It overrides the -d option and the default output filename.
    </option>
    <option short="j" long="joint" arg="processes">
      The maximum number of tracks to convert at one time.
      If one has multiple CPUs or CPU cores, allowing
      track2track(1)
      to use all of them simultaneously can greatly increase encoding speed.
    </option>
  </options>
  <options category="CD lookup">
    <option short="M" long="metadata-lookup">
      perform metadata lookup for converted tracks
    </option>
    <option long="musicbrainz-server" arg="hostname">
      the MusicBrainz server name to query for metadata
    </option>
    <option long="musicbrainz-port" arg="port">
      the MusicBrainz port to query for metadata
    </option>
    <option long="no-musicbrainz">
      don't query MusicBrainz for metadata
    </option>
    <option long="freedb-server" arg="hostname">
      the FreeDB server name to query for metadata
    </option>
    <option long="freedb-port" arg="port">
      the FreeDB port to query for metadata
    </option>
    <option long="no-freedb">
      don't query FreeDB for metadata
    </option>
    <option short="I" long="interactive">
      edit metadata in interactive mode prior to converting tracks
    </option>
    <option short="D" long="default">
      When multiple metadata choices are available,
      select the first one automatically.
      This option has no effect when used with -I
    </option>
  </options>
  <options category="metadata">
    <option long="replay-gain">
      add ReplayGain metadata to newly created tracks
    </option>
    <option long="no-replay-gain">
      do not add ReplayGain metadata to newly created tracks
    </option>
  </options>
  <examples>
    <example>
      <description>
        Convert all the WAVE files in the current working directory to MP3s
        at the default quality:
      </description>
      <command>track2track -t mp3 *.wav</command>
    </example>
    <example>
      <description>
        Convert all of the FLAC files in sourcedir to
        Ogg Vorbis files and place them in targetdir:
      </description>
      <command>track2track -t ogg -d targetdir sourcedir/*.flac</command>
    </example>
    <example>
      <description>
        Convert all of the WAVE files in sourcedir to
        FLAC files, 2 at a time and at the highest possible compression
        (quality 8):
      </description>
      <command>track2track -t flac -j 2 -q 8 sourcedir/*.wav</command>
    </example>
  </examples>
</manpage>
